[Kevin Flynn] The Grid.
A digital frontier.
A world beyond the screen
as real as our own.
I can picture it.
Clusters of information
rising like cities.
Programs as complex
as you and me.
In just a few years,
we're gonna be able
to enter this world.
And a few years after that,
well, this world
will come into ours.
Intelligent life
from inside the machine.
I, for one,
can't wait to meet it.
Our lead story,
Encom CEO and video game icon
Kevin Flynn has disappeared.
He was best known
for designing Tron
and Space Paranoids,
the best-selling video games
in history.
The company that started
at Kevin Flynn's arcade
in the 1980s
has faced years
of corporate turmoil.
Can it find its way to
the victory screen once again?
It's a sister-act for Encom.
Eve and Tess Kim
take the reins
of the massive tech company
after Sam Flynn resigns
for personal reasons.
[reporter 1] Encom's rebound
under the Kim sisters'
leadership
has competitors
rushing to respond.
Software giant
Dillinger Systems
appoints its new CEO,
Julian Dillinger,
who vows to restore
his grandfather's legacy.
The race between Encom
and Dillinger Systems heats up
as new CEOs Julian Dillinger
and the Kim sisters
square off.
[Tess] Here at Encom,
we believe the beauty of AI
is not the ability to build
smarter weapons
but to uplift humanity,
feed the hungry,
cure the sick,
educate the world.
[reporter 2] Rival CEOs
Julian Dillinger and Eve Kim
have gone quiet
in recent months,
raising speculation
the two companies
are very close
to a substantial
technological breakthrough.
[Robin Roberts]
One that has the potential
to transform humanity
in ways we have
never seen before.
The future may well lie
in the hands
of whoever gets there first.
[beeping]
[♪ electronic music playing]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[all grunting, groaning]
[groaning, grunting]
[inhales deeply, panting]
[whirring]
[breathing heavily]
[device whirring]
[disembodied voice] Welcome.
Who are you?
I am your creator.
And who am I?
[inhales]
Mmm.
Not "who." What.
You are Dillinger Systems
security software.
Program name, Ares.
Defender of the Grid.
You are Master Control.
Ares.
I am Master Control.
[♪ electronic music playing]
[device whirring, beeps]
So, you made it.
I had a feeling
that you would.
I always dreamed that
we would do this together.
I'll admit,
not exactly like this.
But I'm glad you're here.
I'm really glad.
And, Evie,
remember I'm still here.
Even if you can't see me.
I love you.
- [person] Oh, my God. Um, Eve.
- [door opens]
I'm not sure you
actually told me
we'd be stealing energy
from the power grid.
Wow. So this is where
she kept coming back to, huh?
To be this disconnected
from the world?
[chuckles]
That is dedication, my friend.
Wow.
It looks like your sister
had a little crush.
Yeah. She was so sure
Flynn left us the answer.
Like on a floppy disk?
Poor Flynn lived
before the cloud, huh?
Hey, are you still
gonna be doing
CEO-type stuff
while we're out here?
You know, like,
earnings calls,
and the launch
of Panic City and stuff.
Let's just get this done.
Dude, I can make breakfast
burritos right here.
Hell yeah.
[exhales]
This is for you, Tess.
[beeps]
[person] Members of the board,
for over 40 years,
my family at Dillinger Systems
has battled Encom
for control of the future.
You put me in charge
of the company
to ensure our victory.
Today...
[chuckling] I make it so.
Imagine if all our
digital prowess
wasn't just digital.
What if anything we could
dream in the machine
could become a reality here?
What if we could
build the bridge
between two previously
walled-off worlds?
So much talk of AI
in big tech today.
Virtual worlds,
what are they gonna look like?
When will we get there?
Well, folks.
We're not going there.
They are coming here.
[announcer 1 on PA] Attention,
please put on
your safety glasses now.
[alarm bell ringing]
[announcer 2 on PA]
Laser systems activated.
Power fluctuations
are nominal.
[announcer 1]
Warning, stand clear.
[announcer 2] Outputting
from Dillinger Systems server.
[lasers whirring]
[announcer 3] Raw material
inflow initiated.
[electricity pulsating,
crackling]
[♪ electronic music playing]
[inhales, exhales]
[announcer 2]
T-minus ten, nine,
eight, seven,
six, five,
four, three,
two, one...
Transfer complete.
I present
the Dillinger Systems
Amphibious
Rapid-response Tank.
The DART.
Digitally modeled
inside our server,
output using our patented
laser technology.
There's an M1 rifle gun,
two M240 machine guns.
It's got a top speed of
75 miles per hour.
Durability, you find a wall,
this thing is gonna
drive through it.
This is full-scale war,
five minutes' notice.
So, if we can create
the hardware of the future,
then why not
the soldier to operate it?
[♪ ominous music playing]
[all gasp]
Ladies and gentlemen,
I would like you to meet Ares.
This is the most sophisticated
security program ever written.
Do you wanna shake his hand?
Go ahead. He doesn't bite.
Ares has billions of lines
of code unique to him.
[board member] Is it alive?
[Julian] That depends
on your definition, Stuart.
[board members murmuring]
[Julian] Because unlike you,
he's biblically strong,
lightning fast,
and supremely intelligent.
He is fully proprietary
and 100% expendable.
Ares is the ultimate soldier.
He needs no food, no water,
sheds no blood.
And if, by some miracle,
he is struck down
on the battlefield,
I will simply
make you another.
[thunder rumbling]
[General] With all that
sophisticated code,
what makes you think
you can contain it?
I can assure you, General,
the most advanced
fail-safe mechanisms
and restriction protocols
are in place.
Ares is predictable,
controllable
and fully aligned.
Southerly front
with isentropic lift,
turning cyclonic.
Predicted precipitation:
2.6 inches.
I hope that you brought
your umbrellas.
[all chuckling]
I have to hand it to you,
Julian.
You promised a big win
and this is even bigger
than any of us
could've imagined.
- [applause]
- [Julian] Thank you.
My grandfather started
Dillinger Corporation
long before anybody heard
the term "cybersecurity."
Military AI is the future.
The question is not whether
the car should be built.
The car is...
being built right now.
The question is...
who's holding the keys?
[engines revving]
[fireflies buzzing]
[sighs] That was
quite some parlor trick.
- Time?
- Forty-four seconds.
"I hope you
brought your umbrellas."
Oh, was that in the script,
or was he just
having a moment?
Elisabeth Dillinger,
eldest daughter of founder
Edward Dillinger, deceased.
Longtime CEO during a
relatively unremarkable period
of corporate history
before being superseded
by your only son.
It's a pleasure.
Unremarkable?
Market share was up 12%
during my tenure.
That's hardly...
And anyway, we don't say
it "superseded," we...
[sighs]
...we call it "giving birth."
Of course.
[beeping]
[distorted] It's an honor
to meet my creator's creator.
Oh, well, here we go.
- [armor beeping]
- [groaning]
[Elisabeth] I noticed
you left out the part
where you can't seem to keep
this thing of yours alive
- for more than 25 minutes.
- Twenty-nine.
Deceiving your investors,
Julian,
is hardly a business model.
Whoever controls
the Permanence Code
controls the future.
We have to win.
[♪ tense music playing]
Look, I...
admire your vision.
Straighten up.
However, the board will only
stand behind you
for another six months...
if you're lucky.
But if it doesn't work...
all of this goes away, darling.
Everything we have built
for the past 40 years.
What if I said
I had found a way?
[footsteps receding]
[gasping]
[panting]
[dings]
[grunts] Oh. I think this is
my 95th breakfast burrito,
and, honestly, can't get
enough. Isn't that wild?
Well...
Nice to see Tess
wasn't the only
obsessive one in the family.
"Yeah, Seth, you're right.
Sorry, I should pay
more attention to you."
"Oh, don't worry about it."
Okay. [scoffs]
[keyboard clacking]
- I'm sorry.
- Get out of here.
Look, three months in sub-zero
is a long time, I get it.
Yeah, and four days,
ten hours, 32 minutes.
Who's counting, really?
You know...
[computer beeping]
Hold on.
[Seth] What do you mean?
What?
[keyboard clacking]
[♪ victory jingle plays]
Seth.
- What, you found something?
- I think so.
[Seth] The line of code.
That's how he hid it,
it's two lines.
[Seth] Whoa.
That looks like
a double helix.
It is a double helix.
Tess would've loved this.
[Seth] Wait. Are you serious?
So no more
"29 minutes and out"?
If this is what I think it is,
it's the Permanence Code.
[whispers] Okay.
Encom offline trial 317a-1.
Permanence Code implemented.
Testing for asset stability
beyond current
29-minute barrier.
Go.
[breathing heavily]
- Ready when you are.
- Okay.
[beeping]
[machine humming]
[♪ energetic music plays]
It's all in the wrists, baby.
[exhales deeply]
[chuckles]
That never gets old.
[Eve] Trial commenced.
Twenty-nine minutes
and counting down.
[sighs]
[sighs] Let's see
if you last this time.
[Julian]
Ares is the ultimate soldier.
If by some miracle
he is struck down
on the battlefield,
I will simply
make you another.
[Julian, Ares]
Fully proprietary, 100%...
[Ares] ...expendable.
- Athena.
- [Athena] Welcome back, sir.
All units are online
and ready for inspection.
So how was it?
[Ares] It was interesting.
Different this time.
I met a mother and a son.
It was raining.
The condensed moisture
of the atmosphere
falling visibly
in separate drops.
I could almost feel it.
Feel? I don't understand.
[Eve on voicemail]
This is Eve.
Get sensible and text.
Hey, Eve. It's Erin. Got Ajay
for you again. Hit us back.
- [line beeps]
- Still straight to voicemail.
[scoffs]
CEO of a Fortune 500 company
and your phone's down
on our biggest night?
Goddamn it.
Where the hell are you, Eve?
[emcee]
All right, Paranoia-Con!
[crowd cheers]
In five, four,
three, two, one.
[timer beeping]
[exhales deeply, gasps]
Did we just do it?
Dude, it's still there!
Dude, we just changed
the world, man!
[echoing] You did it, Eve!
Oh, my God, you did it.
[Robin Roberts on TV]
Big news out of Encom tonight.
CEO Eve Kim will not attend
the highly anticipated
launch event
for the company's new game,
Space Paranoids: Panic City.
Kim, the visionary designer
behind the relaunch of
the blockbuster franchise...
Well, I spoke to several
of our board members,
and needless to say
they are impressed.
[TV continues, indistinct]
Julian.
- [Julian] Just carry on.
- Yes, sir.
What are you doing?
[Julian] Oh, just trying to
change the world, Mother.
What's going on?
You're hacking Encom?
Just a peek
over the garden wall.
No one will notice.
What makes you think
that Encom
is any closer to finding it?
Because I know who else
is looking for it, all right?
Who?
Eve Kim.
She's following
in her sister's footsteps.
She's after
the Permanence Code.
I can feel it.
So I'm gonna find her,
and when I do...
No, I don't like it.
It's too risky, Julian.
Oops.
[♪ intense music plays]
[slurps]
[Pete on PA]
Security breach in all zones.
[Ares breathes deeply]
Programs,
our directive is clear.
Penetrate the server core and
extract Eve Kim's user file.
[backstage AD]
Live in five, four, three...
[crowd cheering]
Space Paranoids fans,
are you ready?
[♪ "Paranoid" playing]
Put your hands together
for Encom CTO, Ajay Singh!
- It's cowboy time.
- Oh, no.
[Ajay] Whoo!
Nice to see you!
Hello.
Thank you.
What's up, Paranoia-Con?
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[Ares panting]
I'm going in.
[Ares groaning, grunting]
[Julian] I'm in.
I'm a genius! Who knew
you raised a genius, Mother?
I'm in!
In deep shit.
[sighs]
[Ares breathing deeply]
[alarm blaring]
Initiate containment protocols
and pull all network access.
We need a response now.
Initiate security protocol.
[Dr. Fei-Fei Li on video]
People are trusting
artificial intelligence
with their lives.
Are you comfortable with this?
Well, look.
For every doomsday scenario,
there's
a medical breakthrough,
scientific discovery.
So maybe what emerges from
the unknown isn't so scary.
What if its major malfunction
is just benevolence?
What is this? What's he doing?
But still, would you prefer
to talk to a real person?
Of course,
but what if that person
is no longer in your life?
No longer here? [echoing]
[computer hums]
[alarm blares]
[Ares breathing heavily]
I've got the file.
[Elisabeth] Congratulations.
Now get out of there
while you still can.
[♪ intense music plays]
[shouting]
Programs, we fight.
[breathes sharply]
[grunts]
- [Encom guard screams]
- [grunts]
[groans]
Yes!
Thank you so much.
What do Paranoiacs do?
[audience]
Grind you into dust!
[Caius groans]
[Ares] Caius.
He's dysfunctional. Leave him.
[Caius grunts, screams]
[Ares]
You're gonna make it, Caius.
Sometimes you have to
sacrifice your knight
to expose their queen.
[Caius panting]
[Ares, Athena scream]
...to debut the latest version
of Space Paranoids: Panic City
with the world.
- [fan A] What's up, bro?
- [fan B] What is that?
- [fan C] This is crazy.
- [fan D] Have you seen this?
[security] Mr. Singh,
you need to come with me.
This is
a technical difficulty.
- We'll be back.
- [security] This way, sir.
[fan E]
Everything's gone down.
[Julian Hologram]
Well done, Master Control.
Eve Kim's file acquired.
Objective achieved.
Sir, I'm curious
why the Program Caius
was not reconstituted.
[♪ sentimental music plays]
I'm curious
why you are curious.
Caius was dysfunctional,
so he was deleted.
Just like any program
that operates outside
their directive can be.
Do you understand?
Acknowledge, Master Control.
Of course.
We are 100% expendable.
New mission, Master Control.
Locate Eve Kim.
Yes, sir.
Seems like we had
a little cyber breach, Jules.
But then of course
you knew that.
It looks like
the whole world knows, buddy.
Might wanna stay off
the socials for a few days.
You wanna play games with me?
Let's play games, Julian.
I heard about your cute
little pitch to the board.
But you left off one
key detail from your deck.
Did you tell them
the shot clock expires
at 29 minutes?
Don't make me call The Journal
and tell them
you're making promises
you can't keep.
Promises?
What, you mean like the one
that your CEO
will be in office
running the company?
Something in the water
over there, Ajay?
I mean, first, wonder boy
Sam Flynn, now his successor.
Where is she, Ajay?
Do you even know where she is?
Maybe you're right.
Maybe Eve went nuts.
Maybe she went AWOL
and left the country,
or maybe...
she's holed up off the grid
looking for the same
thing you are.
And I know who my money's on.
You mean what's left of it
after tonight.
End of line!
[line beeps]
[sighs] I hate that man.
[Seth] Thank you so much.
You know,
I made those oranges.
It's a long story. [chuckles]
[Eve humming]
- [phone beeping]
- Stop, stop, stop.
[chuckles] What are you doing?
- 1913 messages. Popular.
- [Eve] Wow.
Oh, it's Ajay.
Yeah, that's you.
- Ajay, are you there?
- [Ajay] Am I here?
A brute force attack
took down our servers
during our biggest
product launch in years.
Everything we've built
is melting down.
You need to get back here
right now.
I found it, Ajay. It's real.
Right where
Tess thought it would be.
Flynn had it all along.
Are you talking
about the Permanence Code?
Yeah. Four hours and counting.
Zero degradation,
no instability.
It's incredible.
Wait a second.
Did you say four hours?
- [Eve] Yeah, four hours.
- My God.
He must know, Evie.
- I just spoke to Dillinger.
- Wait.
- You just spoke to Dillinger?
- [Ajay] He's looking
for the code,
and he thinks you are too.
We gotta move on this.
Eve,
you've done a great thing.
Tess did a great thing.
I'm en route to Encom.
We'll secure the code,
I have it with me on a drive.
[computer chimes]
[♪ sentimental music plays]
[Eve on video]
We're relaunching Paranoia!
Boy, it's your birthday.
- [Eve] Yeah! Ajay.
- Boy, it's your birthday.
[man on video]
Yo, what's up, Eve?
You've got some news
for the freaks at home?
[Eve on video] Um, hi.
[Ares] "I am fearless,
and therefore powerful."
So, apparently we just sold
our ten millionth unit!
Evie, Space Paranoids.
Kevin Flynn,
wherever the hell he is,
has a big smile on his face.
Oh, you crushed it.
No. [chattering]
[both giggling]
♪ Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Tess ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
- [Eve breathing shakily]
- [heart monitor beeping]
[newscaster] Breaking news.
Encom's Head
of Special Projects,
Tess Kim, died today
after a long battle
with cancer.
Her sister, Eve Kim, could not
be reached for comment.
[♪ sentimental music playing]
[computer beeping]
[Ares gasps]
Permanence.
Checkmate.
And so our heroes
venture off into the night.
Nothing but
the clothes on their backs
and, well,
a six-million-dollar
particle laser
that creates organic material
out of nowhere,
which is kind of crazy, right?
Keep the equipment safe
and just... lay low.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Hey.
We got this.
[engines revving]
[♪ ominous music playing]
[bell rings]
[technician A on radio]
Launch directive
on countdown one. Comm check.
[technician B] GNC
[technician A]
Printing in progress.
[technician B] Stage one.
Chamber pressure is nominal.
[technician C]
Envac engine chill has begun.
Stage one load is complete.
[announcement on PA]
Transfer complete.
[♪ electronic music playing]
[whirring]
You have 29 minutes
to bring me Eve Kim.
[engines revving]
[singer vocalizing]
[engine revs]
[police scanner]
Asset deployment confirmed.
Vehicles en route.
[Ares] Target identified.
Goddamn it. I'm awesome!
[Ares] Intercepting now.
[engines revving]
[tires squealing]
[Ares] Eyes on the target.
[police scanner]
Coordinating containment
for suspect fleeing eastbound.
[Eve] What?
[siren blaring]
[police officer on speaker]
You, on the motorcycle!
Pull over.
[both gasp]
[pedestrians shriek]
- [horns honking]
- [tires screeching]
[panting]
[Eve] Come on.
[groans]
[panting]
[light cycle clicks]
Where'd she go?
[screaming] Come on!
[panting] Okay.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
[whirring]
[♪ triumphant
electronic music plays]
[Eve] Oh, my God.
Come on. Come on.
- [exclaims]
- [yelps]
[screaming]
[panting]
What?
[Eve screaming, muffled]
[pants] Okay.
- [screams]
- [horn honking]
[breathing heavily]
Oh, my God. Okay. [shrieks]
Oh, my God! [screaming]
[♪ suspenseful music plays]
[exhales]
Prepare the particle laser.
Time to move to plan B.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
[Eve groans]
Yeah.
[♪ suspenseful music
continues]
Oh, yeah. You wanna play?
[gasping]
[grunts]
[panting]
[electricity pulsating]
[Ares grunting]
[grunts]
[footsteps approaching]
What are you?
I am Master Control.
[helicopter blades whirring]
What do you want?
I want the code.
Well...
It's gone.
[groaning]
No, it's not.
I have her in my sights.
Establishing connection
to the Grid now.
Ready to transfer
in T-minus 15 seconds.
You're... a program.
[grunting]
You're timing out.
[grunting continues]
[police officer]
Get on the ground!
[screaming]
[groans]
[Julian]
Transfer her into the Grid.
[groans]
[reporter on TV] I'm on
the ground in downtown.
And I can tell you,
this was no elaborate stunt.
- Three riders...
- What have you done?
How could you be so reckless?
[Julian] When the world sees
what I have created,
all will be forgiven.
Is that what you think?
You think that
you're in control of this?
You're not.
Believing we can
change the world
is what keeps
this company relevant.
But it's also what can burn it
to the ground.
And your job
is knowing the difference.
[Voice of the Grid] Transfer
of biological life-form
in progress.
Digital reconstruction
initiated.
[grid tech 1]
Twenty percent digitized.
Forty percent digitized.
Sixty-five percent digitized.
Ninety-five percent digitized.
[Voice of the Grid]
Digitization complete.
Run diagnostics
and scan for corruption.
[♪ sinister music plays]
[Voice of the Grid] Eve Kim
identity disk activated.
- [computer hums]
- [gasps]
Wow.
Where am I?
Dillinger Systems
Central Processing Unit.
Wait. What?
We have identified
the sequence.
The user possesses the code.
The code?
I don't have the code.
I destroyed the drive.
[Athena] Silence, user.
The code isn't only
on a drive.
The code is inside of you.
Whether you remember it
or not,
you've seen it
and that is enough.
Sir, her disk is showing
signs of instability.
Define instability.
Extraction of the code
may result in de-resolution
of the carrier.
[Athena]
The directive is clear.
Isolate the thread
and commence extraction.
- [grid tech 1] Copy.
- [weapons buzz]
Wait. No, no, no.
Stop.
Athena is correct.
There's only one user
whose directive we follow.
[computer chimes]
[computer beeping]
[Julian]
What will remain of the user
if she were to suffer
de-resolution?
Nothing, sir.
No trace of her existence
on the Grid?
None, sir.
Extract the code
and delete the carrier.
But, sir, extracting
the Permanence Code
would delete the carrier from
the Grid and from your world.
Once upon a time,
there was a weapon
and its name was Ares.
And Ares obeyed every command
of Julian Dillinger,
and Julian Dillinger
made a trillion dollars.
And wrote his name
on the face of time in blood.
Now, whatever PEBKAC error
is behind these feelings,
I'm going to find it
and rip it out of you.
Do I make myself clear?
[♪ tense music plays]
Perfectly.
Program dismissed.
The creature also said,
"I am fearless,
and therefore powerful."
[♪ dramatic music plays]
[Athena] Well?
[Ares] The user is indisposed.
Hold extraction
until further directive.
- Indisposed?
- [Ares] Correct.
Define indisposed.
He's stuck in traffic.
No, he's at the opera.
He's standing on
the top of Mount Fuji
in a pair of green socks
playing "Pistol Packin' Mama"
on the mandolin.
I gave you an order.
The creator is indisposed.
Hold extraction until
we receive further directive.
Do I make myself clear?
Yes, sir.
Programs dismissed.
Can I trust you?
It's a complicated question.
How much time you got?
Sixty seconds. Answer now.
Your life cycle
depends upon it.
I don't have a life cycle.
Yes, you do.
For another 54 seconds.
Can I trust you?
Um, I'd like to think so,
but probably not.
Where is Master Control?
Sir, Master Control
is exhibiting
signs of malfunction.
Hmm.
Any threat to the directive
must be eliminated.
Extract the code
and delete them both.
- Do you understand?
- Hmm.
- [Ares] And Julian Dillinger?
- You can't trust him.
For him, everyone
and everything is expendable.
I miscalculated.
We have a new directive.
Athena, it doesn't have to
be like this.
Delete him!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[thuds, echoing]
[groans]
[all screaming]
[groans, panting]
[screams]
[gasping]
[♪ mysterious music plays]
[panting]
[light cycle hums]
[revving]
I'm okay. I'm okay.
[Athena] They're headed
towards the Transfer Portal.
We lost them in the Grid,
ma'am.
Preparing the drones.
Delete Ares, and bring
the user back to me.
[grid tech 1] Copy.
[drones hum]
What happened back there?
I disobeyed my directive.
Which was?
To retrieve the code
from your disk
and delete the carrier.
Dillinger told you
to delete me?
Hang on!
[Athena] Where are they?
[grid tech 2] Scanning
quadrants three and four.
[grid tech 1] Sector 18 clear.
[engine revving]
Where are we going?
[Ares] Transfer Portal.
It's the only way
out of the Grid.
You'll be reconstituted
in the real world
exactly as you were before, hypothetically.
[chuckles]
- Hypothetically?
- Probably.
[grid tech 1]
We have movement in sector 72.
[grid tech 2]
Zeroing in on target.
Shut them down!
[Ares] You wanna get home,
I can help you.
But I need something
in return.
I told you
I don't have the code.
You found it once,
you can find it again.
So you can give it
to Dillinger?
Not for Dillinger.
For me.
Do we have a deal?
[♪ mysterious music plays]
So, do we have a deal?
Yes. Yes, I know
where to find the code.
Just get me out of here.
[grid tech 1] Target
approaching Transfer Portal
in 45 seconds.
[grid tech 2] Drones
malfunctioned and offline.
[screams]
[PA] Attention.
Please stand clear.
[grid tech 1]
Override not responding.
Transfer bay is online.
- [Elisabeth] What is it?
- [Julian] Who authorized this?
[Cross] Sir, this originated
inside the Grid.
Julian?
[grid tech 1] All agents
report to transfer bay floor
immediately.
[PA] Clear the area.
Get everybody out of here.
[PA] Unauthorized printing
in progress.
Clear the central area.
[technicians clamoring]
[PA]Transfer complete.
[Cross] Move in.
[bell ringing]
- [chokes]
- [gasps]
[grunts]
[timer beeping]
[Julian] Well, well, well.
Just got double-crossed
by my program.
It wants the Permanence Code
for itself.
Eve, is that the deal?
It gets you out of the Grid,
you turn Pinocchio
into a real boy?
Well, you're missing the part
where you're willing
to commit murder
for a piece of software.
[Julian] Is that what it said?
Twenty-eight minutes,
41 seconds.
Ares!
I do hope
this works out for you.
There's no second chances,
no do-overs.
These are the last 29 minutes
you'll ever have!
Better make it count!
[♪ tense music plays]
[grunting]
- [tires screech]
- [horn honks]
I should've majored
in English lit.
[lasers humming]
[exhales deeply]
[PA]Transfer complete.
[Julian] Your directive is
to find Eve Kim,
return her to the Grid and
get me the Permanence Code.
By any means necessary.
Do you understand
your directive,
Master Control?
At your command, sir.
Attagirl.
[♪ intense music plays]
Ticktock!
Oh!
Oh! [chuckles]
Whoo!
Now that is the coolest thing
I have ever seen.
[inhales deeply]
Do you know
who Kevin Flynn was?
Of course.
Visionary programmer,
pioneer of
The Digital Frontier.
Disappeared 1989.
I found the Permanence Code
on a backup of Flynn's server.
That server is at Encom's
office downtown.
But we can make it within...
Twenty-six minutes,
nine seconds.
Eve, your plan contains
two major flaws.
Okay.
One, Encom is 9.2 miles away,
given our present speed
and suboptimal
choice of vehicle...
Oh, my God.
Two, we're gonna need
a particle laser.
We need a phone.
[tires squeal]
[tires screech]
I cannot believe
I'm doing this.
Excuse me. Do you see this?
This is me.
If you let me use
your cell phone,
my assistant
will wire you $10,000.
I just need your phone.
[♪ rock music playing softly]
Seth, where are you?
[Seth] Eve,
whose phone is this?
Listen to me. I need you
at Encom in 15 minutes.
Hey, is everything okay?
Seth, bring
the particle laser.
- Encom, 15 minutes. Got it.
- [tires screech, horn honks]
[engine revs]
That's my car.
[Eve]
I'll wire you another 50K.
Hey, that's my car!
Four-cylinder
with 138 horsepower.
Clash.
Hey! That's my car!
That's my car!
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[engine revving]
[chuckles] God.
[truck horn blares]
- Eve?
- Yeah?
I was thinking about the time
you told your sister
that you wished you never
relaunched Space Paranoids.
Then you went on
to say that...
Oh, my God. Of course.
You read all my texts.
Yeah. Yeah, I've read
them all. Every single one.
Wow.
Most of it was information
of a personal nature.
Some of it, highly personal.
And I just can't get enough.
What?
Depeche Mode. Number eight
on the UK singles chart, 1982.
I find their brand of
pithy, catchy,
timeless and true
'80s electropop
to be deeply invigorating.
[♪ "Just Can't Get Enough"
playing]
Sixteen minutes, 20 seconds.
[chuckles] Okay. So you like,
uh, '80s pop
and, uh, cyber-spying on me.
I was directed
to kill you, Eve.
Hacking seems pretty tame
by comparison.
[♪ "Just Can't Get Enough"
continues]
[engine revving]
- Oh, my God.
- For the record,
I don't think you have
anything to be ashamed of.
Space Paranoids
has entertained
hundreds of millions.
Plus, it's a pretty cool game.
Anyway, you told your sister
that designing games
left you feeling
hollow, broken.
Was it that your work
was about
entertainment and profits
and her work was about
improving the human condition?
Your texts suggest
a certain fixation
with not being able to live up
to her standards,
which must have
been complicated,
especially considering
she was the younger sister.
Okay. Watch it.
By the way, I don't think
you should quit.
What do you mean?
Your plan upon returning
from the mountains,
if I read you correctly,
was to hand over
the Permanence Code to Encom
and then let them figure out
what to do with it next, no?
[♪ sentimental music playing]
Yeah. Now I understand.
You completed her work
as a way to
stay connected to her.
Huh.
And now what?
Being human is hard.
The things that make life
great are the same things
that make it excruciating,
like love, loss.
You must miss her very much.
[tires screech]
[passerby] Hey, hey.
[person 1] What the hell?
[person 2] Whoa.
Check this guy out.
- Well, look who it is!
- Hi.
Glad you could join us,
Miss Kim.
People have been wondering
where you've been.
Long time no see. Bit of
a rush, so I'm just gonna...
- Eve.
- Mm-hmm?
You gotta bring your badge.
Okay, yeah, Jolene...
Hello, Jolene. Hi.
Got her badge right here.
Okay. His too?
Uh, no. He's not with us.
- Yes, he is.
[elevator chimes]
[♪ "Summer Breeze" plays]
Let's start literally
anywhere you'd like. Um...
This is my boyfriend, Ares.
No. Master Control
Security Program
from Dillinger's Grid.
Ares, Seth. Seth, Ares.
Oh, God.
Pleasure.
Hey, that's nice.
Um, so, Ares, like, as in,
the god of war, Ares?
Yeah.
Cool. You're Greek.
That's awesome.
So when you say that
he's the security program,
do you mean he's like...
- Yeah. He's not human.
- He's not human.
- Mm-hmm.
- Originated inside a GPU.
[chuckles] Okay. Is this
for the Christmas video?
[elevator chimes]
Three minutes
to de-resolution.
[Eve]
Can you work with that, Seth?
[Seth] Yeah.
Don't need help, guys.
Okay.
Oh, boy.
[Eve] So, this is where
I found the Permanence Code
on a backup of this server.
Talk about first gen.
Talk about a piece of garbage.
Am I right? [chuckles]
That was super insensitive
to your ancestors,
and I'm so sorry.
It's gonna take me
a few minutes to set this up.
No rush. Two minutes,
18 seconds.
[Eve] Soon as the laser's up,
we'll send you into the Grid.
Once you're in there, you'll
have to run your own search,
but believe me, the Permanence
Code is in there.
So what should I expect?
Uh, if I were to guess?
Think '80s.
'80s.
I like the '80s.
One minute, 31 seconds.
[Seth] Okay. Come on.
[Seth] Please, help me.
Okay, all set.
Adapters.
[laser beeping]
[Eve]
Once you locate the code,
get to the portal
and we'll bring you out.
I'll activate it
from the outside.
Can I trust you?
I'd like to think so,
- but probably not.
- Probably not.
Yeah.
Well, it's a good thing
we don't have trust issues
because if we did,
I could imagine that--
I could pull the plug
and leave you in a Grid less
complex than my smartphone
for all eternity.
The thought had
crossed my mind.
Mine too.
Oh, mine three.
Sorry. Just...
Well, here goes nothing.
Or here goes something.
You're right.
I do miss her.
All the time.
[jump jet rumbling]
Athena. She's here.
Whoa. What is that?
Athena.
Wait. Who?
Seth, the laser. The laser!
Okay, initiating systems now.
Connecting to the Flynn Grid.
[Seth] Firing up the laser.
Wait, what's she doing?
She's waiting for me
to time out...
...and then she'll come
for you.
[Eve]
We're almost there. Get ready.
[Seth] Come on.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
[Eve] Ares, move
in front of the laser.
[Seth] Okay. We're ready.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Change of plans.
- No, no, no!
- [Seth] No, wait!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ inspirational music
playing]
Well, that actually worked.
[chuckles]
- He's inside.
- Great.
Move!
[♪ intense music plays]
[breathing heavily]
[debris clattering]
Eve.
[yelps]
[Athena]
Time to get back to the Grid.
Leave her alone!
You're very persistent, user.
[laser hums]
[water splashing]
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[Seth groans]
[groans]
What?
Hi.
Did we win?
- She'll be back.
- [coughs]
Ares.
He can't get out.
The '80s.
[electrical whirring]
[♪ mysterious music playing]
Binary digit.
- You're a Bit.
- Yes.
I'm looking for something.
Can you help me find it?
Yes, yes, yes.
[electronic beeping]
[♪ majestic music plays]
[whirring]
Classic.
I'm surrounded by
the wide-scale destruction
caused by tonight's
brazen attack
that left local residents
stunned.
There is speculation that
Dillinger Systems
had something to do
with the event,
and authorities have
remained tight-lipped.
- [alarm ringing]
- [newscaster] Citizens
and authorities alike
want to know...
was this a coordinated attack
or technology run amok?
[Julian sighs] What now?
[alarm continues]
[gasps]
What is this?
Where's my code?
Hey!
What are you doing?
Who gave you this directive?
You did, sir.
What is this?
[computer voice] Warning.
No, no, no.
This is too big, Athena.
Too big!
[Elisabeth] Julian!
You're done.
The board is moving
as we speak
to strip you of your title,
and I'm reassuming control
of the company.
No, you can't do that.
Can't do that!
[Elisabeth] Yes, I can.
This is not going any further.
You can't...
My first order of business
is shutting down
- The Permanence Project.
- No, no, no. Mom, no!
[grunts, gasps]
- [gasping]
- Don't be afraid.
We gave a thousand lives
for the Grid.
You only have to give one.
[echoing] No, no, no.
Mom!
Impediment eliminated.
What did you do?
I am fulfilling my directive.
Capture Eve Kim.
Return her to the Grid
by any means necessary.
Scanning
for further impediments.
[Elisabeth groaning]
[computer voice]
Please keep clear.
Hang on, Mom. Hang on.
[Elisabeth groans]
No!
[electronic beep]
[breathes deeply]
[whooshing sound]
[chuckles]
[whirring]
Flynn.
Greetings, program.
[♪ ominous music playing]
[people clamoring]
Oh, God. Not good.
[reporter]
There are multiple reports
of fire and destruction
on the upper levels...
Um, Eve?
What the hell happened
to our office?
Ajay, look, there's no time.
The Dillingers transported me
inside their server
by reversing the direction
of a particle laser.
- Not this one. Theirs.
- That's impossible.
No. A scary lady did it, man.
She threw me... It was wild.
I saw a complex world
where packets of energy
move as vehicles
that trail by lines of light.
And-And programs
take on human form.
I met the most advanced AI
known to mankind.
His name is Ares.
Like the god of war, but he's
actually a super nice guy.
- Sorry.
- Right now,
Ares is inside
Flynn's original server.
He's looking
for the Permanence Code.
I have to bring him back here,
and I'm not going to be able
to do that
until we fix this laser.
I don't understand.
Are you alive?
I exist in this moment
because you do.
A reflection of your presence.
What's your story?
I'm Ares, Master Control of
the Dillinger Security Grid.
Dillinger?
Hmm.
Well, we both know
you can't get here from there.
Been someplace else
in between?
What did you make of it
out there?
It's hard to put
in a nutshell.
[chuckles]
You can say that again.
It's hard to put
in a nutshell.
[laughs]
Ah, classic. Humor, man.
Oh.
What are you looking for?
Permanence.
The Permanence Code,
to be exact.
Strange things have
been happening.
I questioned my directive.
I disobeyed my directive.
Mmm.
A malfunctioning program
who wants to live.
Really?
What makes you think
I should help you?
No, it's not about me.
Not anymore.
I have a friend in danger,
and she needs my help.
[Flynn chuckles]
Fascinating.
Hey, Ajay, can you send
the prompt, please?
[Ajay] Sure, yeah.
- Uh, hey, Eve.
- Not now, Seth.
Okay. Hey, are you sure?
Because that looks like
an actual Recognizer
flying towards us.
[♪ tense music playing]
What in God's name is that?
It's Athena.
She's back.
As long as the Dillinger
Network is online,
she'll keep coming.
If she gets me,
she gets the Permanence Code.
The laser. Athena's laser!
The Dillingers run a wireless
direct link protocol,
so let's use
what's left of the laser
to ping the network
and trace a path home.
Once you have a connection,
then you can nuke
the whole Dillinger Grid.
And that's the only way
to stop her for good.
Eve, what are you
talking about?
She's right there.
- I gotta go.
- [Ajay] Wait, what?
I'll keep her away
for as long as I can.
- What?
- I'm gonna buy you some time.
- Eve...
- You guys got this.
- [panting]
- [siren wailing]
[Ares] You're right.
I think there is
something wrong with me.
[Flynn] Or maybe there's
something right with you.
Well, maybe you're
just learning.
That's what we all
ought to be doing.
Back in the day,
when tech was young,
I'd think,
"Damn, we're moving fast."
[sighs] You move fast,
you leave stuff behind.
How many people
born in this century
have even heard of Mozart?
I like Mozart.
[chuckles]
Oh?
That said, if I'm being
honest, I prefer Depeche Mode.
[chuckles]
Really? Why is that?
I know one is considered
the greatest composer
in the history
of Western civilization,
the other a synth pop band
from the '80s,
but I find their balance
of technological exploration
and pop hooks combined with...
Uh, com-- Uh...
combined with, uh...
What's wrong?
I-I can't put my love
of Depeche Mode into words.
It's just a...
Hmm? A what?
A feeling.
[chuckles]
Very good.
Very good, man.
[sniffling]
[gasping] You...
You did this.
[reporter]
And tonight, as military...
[Ajay] Impressive.
Fully segmented
zero trust architecture.
Built to be
totally impregnable
to vertical, lateral
or hybrid attacks.
Damn it.
Can't get a connection, dude.
No luck here either.
[people clamoring]
[officer]
Please, evacuate the area.
[clamoring continues]
[Recognizer whirring]
What is that thing?
- Bring in SWAT!
- Requesting backup.
[♪ ominous music plays]
[Seth] Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
[clamoring]
Come on. A little closer.
[panting]
[pilot 1] Viper-1 to base.
Tally on hostile.
Confirmed visual ID.
Engaging Fox-2. Missile away.
[alarm beeping]
[pilot 2] Splash negative.
Missile intercepted.
Be advised,
enemy fighter escorts inbound
and moving fast.
[commander] Copy, Raven-1.
Assess and report
threat posture.
[pilot 2] Viper-1,
tally multiple bandits.
Hostile intent confirmed.
Mayday. Mayday. I'm hit!
Viper-1. Punching out.
[panting]
Uh, guys? Guys.
Oh, my God.
There's hundreds of 'em.
They're going after Eve.
If we can't access
the Dillinger server,
there's gonna be
nothing left to save.
[♪ intense music plays]
[pilot 2]
Base, this is Raven-1.
Enemy aircraft engaging.
I'm defensive.
Multiple bandits. Redirecting
to primary target.
I'm hit! Punching out.
[gasps, pants]
[grunts]
[♪ gentle electronic
music plays]
[whirring]
Ready?
Hope you are, man,
'cause there's no going back.
Permanence.
Funny.
When I found it,
that's what I called it.
I know better now.
Ought to be called
the Impermanence Code.
The back door to my old lab.
One go-around.
That's all you've got.
One...
is all I want.
Love that!
You keep surprising me!
[groans]
We'll do this
from the ground then.
[laser powering up]
[gasps, pants]
[engines roaring]
...and there are reports that
a civilian may be onboard,
making this
a possible hostage scenario.
[Seth] Athena.
She must've gotten Eve.
[reporter]
...into the mountains.
[officer] Hey, hey, hey!
[tires screech]
[gasps]
[Athena] Soon we'll be back
on the Grid.
[♪ triumphant music playing]
[breathes heavily]
[grunts]
[screams]
[horns blare]
[reporter] General, thank you
for taking the time...
- [distorted beeping]
- ...to speak with us tonight.
Hey, Erin. Seth.
Stop the clock.
No way. You're in?
There's a reason why I have
the corner office, my man.
[groaning softly]
Hey.
[Eve coughs]
You came back.
How did you...
Let's just say I had
a little help from a friend.
[chuckles]
Wait, the Dillinger Grid...
Ajay and Seth, they...
[rumbling]
[♪ tense music playing]
- Go.
- No.
Ares!
What have you done?
You're out of time, Athena.
And you're out of lives.
I'll kill you
and come back for her.
[mechanical whirring]
It's you she wants.
If she gets the code,
she can't be stopped.
You had everything.
- Go.
- No.
The most advanced,
the most powerful,
and you gave it away.
For her?
Go!
This is the end for you.
[♪ exciting music playing]
[grunting]
Payload ready for transfer.
Shipping it.
Let's hope Eve was right.
[alarm blaring]
[computer voice] Alert.
Unknown file incoming.
[groaning]
In pursuit of this life
for yourself,
did you once consider
what that meant for the Grid?
[shouts]
[♪ triumphant music playing]
[Athena shouts]
We were given an order.
It is our purpose.
[groaning]
It's not our purpose.
It's our programming.
Our purpose is yet
to be determined.
- [electronic whirring]
- [Ares grunting]
[all chuckle, sigh]
It's over.
And there's no coming back.
No.
Not this time.
They did it.
[Seth] Oh, my...
[all cheering]
[gasping]
I followed my directive.
I know.
And now...
what is yours?
I'm not sure.
- I guess we'll see.
- [beeping]
[beeping intensifies]
[wheezes]
[reporter]
Dillinger Systems is
under intense scrutiny tonight
as speculation grows around
its potential involvement
in the series
of devastating attacks
that have rocked the city.
Federal authorities
have confirmed
an active investigation into
the company's recent activity,
and many are pointing directly
at CEO Julian Dillinger.
Agents have been deployed
to question the CEO
as well as his mother,
and to locate board members
who will be questioned
on the situation.
Meanwhile,
the city remains in disarray.
Emergency services
are overwhelmed,
while entire neighborhoods
are dealing with
- the wide-scale destruction.
- [police sirens wailing]
[♪ tense music playing]
[exhales sharply]
[grunts]
[officer] Julian Dillinger,
this is the police.
We have you surrounded.
Open the door and come out
with your hands up.
[exhales sharply]
[grunts] Come on.
[gasps]
[officers] Breach!
Police!
Stay where you are!
[officer 1 on radio]
Maintain visuals on all exits.
[officer 2] Charlie-9,
we're at last field location.
Last field location.
Yellow-6, out front.
Let's move. Let's move.
[Eve] Ow.
[Ares] Are you good?
Oh, I think
I broke a rib. [groans]
[both sigh]
[chuckles]
You still gonna quit your job?
No, I'm not
gonna quit anything.
Good.
I have some ideas.
Oh, yeah? Nice.
Well, the world
needs you, Eve.
The Grid needs you.
[chuckles]
Yeah. It's funny, permanence.
A wise man once told me
it should have been called
the "Impermanence Code."
I guess that's
the thing about life.
There's nothing
quite permanent about it.
No.
No, there isn't.
Yeah.
[sirens wailing in distance]
[Eve groans]
So where are you gonna go?
I have some ideas.
Mmm.
[sirens continue]
[police chatter
on loudspeaker]
[narrator] Under the
leadership of CEO Eve Kim,
Encom is
transforming industries...
...and shaping lives in ways
once thought impossible.
Thanks to the discovery
of the Permanence Code,
the company has made
revolutionary advances
growing crops
in climate-vulnerable regions,
developing drugs for
treatment-resistant cancers,
and accelerating
the development
of alternative fuels.
Encom is committed
to exploring
new digital frontiers,
driving progress
at the intersection
of technology and life itself
to improve
the human condition.
In fact, innovation has always
been at the heart of Encom.
In the 1980s,
visionary Kevin Flynn imagined
a future beyond gaming,
a bold leap
into new digital frontiers.
Today, that vision
is a reality.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Postcard?
Who sends a postcard?
Don't know. Didn't read it.
[Ares] Dear Eve,
since I last saw you,
I've been living
what they call "off-grid."
Pun intended.
In my travels,
I've seen incredible things.
Despite its wonder and beauty,
I've come to realize
that life is...
Well, it's hard
to put in a nutshell.
Some days,
I find myself wondering
where we'll be
a hundred years from now...
...and how others like me
might fit into that future.
I feel like I might not be
alone with these questions.
For now,
I don't think the world
is quite ready to meet me,
but I am meeting the world.
And so, when that
introduction finally comes,
as a good friend of mine
once said,
"Maybe what emerges
from the unknown
won't be so scary after all."
Until we meet again,
your friend, Ares.
[sighs]
[♪ "As Alive As You Need Me
To Be" playing]
[electricity crackling]
[grunting]
[coughs, grunts]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[program voice echoing]
Sark...
- [electricity pulsating]
- [screams]
[♪ gentle music playing]
創界網絡
一個數位新領域
數位的世界，跟我們的世界一樣眞實
我能想像
資訊的群落如城市般崛起
與你我一樣複雜的程式
短短幾年後，我們就能進入這個世界
再過幾年
這個世界就會進入我們的世界
來自機器內部的智慧生命
我等不及要見到它了
焦點新聞
英克爾執行長與遊戲巨擘凱文費林失蹤
（最新消息：凱文費林失蹤）
他的設計代表作是《創》和《瘋狂空間》
史上最暢銷的電玩
該公司一九八零年創立於費林的遊戲場
（英克爾企業風暴）
多年來動盪不安
它能再次設法扭轉乾坤嗎？
英克爾的姊妹檔聯手出擊
山姆費林因個人因素請辭後
伊芙與黛絲金接掌這家大型科技公司
英克爾在金氏姊妹領導下重振雄風
讓競爭對手急於因應
軟體大廠狄林傑系統
任命新執行長朱利安狄林傑
他誓言恢復祖父的榮光
英克爾與狄林傑之間的競爭
隨著雙方新執行長相互較勁而白熱化
在英克爾，我們相信人工智慧的優點
不在打造更聰明的武器
而是讓人類更進步
消除飢餓、治療疾病、敎育世界
朱利安狄林傑與對手伊芙金
最近幾個月都保持沉默
讓人懷疑這兩家公司
可能即將達成重大的科技突破
它可能會用前所未見的方式
徹底改變人類社會
未來可能掌握在率先達陣的人手中
（啟動）
（啟動戰神程式）
（系統準備最後戰神啟動）
（進度）
（數位化完成）
（生成式對抗網絡）
（開始）
（蒐集資料中）
（生成式修復程式）
（開始）
（狄林傑系統）
歡迎
你是誰？
我是你的創造者
那我是誰？
（那我是誰？）
不是「誰」，是「什麼」
你是狄林傑系統安全軟體
程式名戰神，創界網絡的捍衛者
你是主控
戰神
我是主控
《創：戰神》
（費林不死）
（英克爾姊妹檔帶來獲利與前景）
（朱利安狄林傑投入人工智慧軍事科技）
（播放）
所以，你到了
我就覺得你會到
我總是夢想我們能一起做到
我承認，我想像的不是這樣
但很高興你在這裡
眞的很高興
伊芙，記住，我還在這裡
即使你看不到我
我愛你
天啊
伊芙
你沒說過我們會從電網
偸電來用吧
哇，這就是她不斷回來的地方？
這麼與世隔絕？眞執著啊，朋友
哇
令妹煞到某人囉
對啊，她堅信費林留了答案給我們
留在磁片上？
可惜費林當時沒有雲端
你在這裡的時候還要當執行長嗎？
開財報電話會議，發表《恐慌城市》
把這搞定吧
我能在這裡做早餐墨西哥捲，好耶
這是為了你，黛絲
（載入磁片中，請稍候）
各位董事會成員
卌多年來，我在狄林傑系統的夥伴
一直與英克爾爭奪未來的控制權
你們讓我主導公司，確保勝利
今天
我做到了
想像我們的數位實力不限於數位領域
要是我們對機器的夢想
都能在這裡實現呢？
要是能為兩個原本分隔的世界
搭起橋梁呢？
如今的科技大企業大談人工智慧
虛擬世界會是什麼樣？
我們何時能抵達？
各位，我們不會去那裡
而是它們會過來
註意，請立刻戴上安全眼鏡
雷射系統啟動，電力波動正常
（雷射校正中）
警告，勿靠近
輸出來自…
（轉移開始）
狄林傑系統伺服器
原始資料流入已開始
倒數十、九
八、七
六、五
四、三、二、一
轉移完成
容我介紹
狄林傑系統兩棲快速反應坦克
達爾特
在伺服器中進行數位建模
利用我們的專利雷射科技輸出
配有M一步槍，兩把M二四零機關槍
最高時速一百廿公里
至於耐用性，找一面牆，它會穿牆而過
這是全面性戰爭，反應時間五分鐘
所以，如果能創造未來的硬體
何不創造士兵來操作它？
各位先生女士，為你隆重介紹戰神
這是史上最精密的安全程式
想和他握手？請便，他不會咬人
戰神有數十億行專屬程式碼
它是活的嗎？
那得看你的定義，史都華
跟你不同，他十分強壯
快如閃電，極具智慧
他全是自有技術，而且隨時能犧牲
戰神是終極士兵
不需要食物飲水，不會流血
如果出現奇蹟，他在戰場上倒下
我就再做一個給你
（聲震波）
程式碼那麼精密
你怎麼控制得了它？
我向你擔保，將軍
最先進的失效安全機制
與限制協定都已就位
戰神可測可控，完全服從
伴隨等熵擡昇的南方鋒面，轉為氣旋
預計降雨六十六毫米
希望你們帶了傘
我必須恭喜你，朱利安
你承諾會大獲全勝
這比我們想像中更了不起
謝謝
我祖父創立狄林傑公司時
根本沒人聽過「網路安全」
軍事人工智慧是未來趨勢
問題不在是否該製造汽車，汽車…
正在製造中
問題是…
誰握有鑰匙？
好炫的小把戲
時間？ -卌四秒
「希望你們帶了傘」
那在劇本裡，還是他即興演出？
伊莉莎白狄林傑
已故創辦人愛德華狄林傑的長女
在公司歷史上平淡無奇的時期
長期擔任執行長，隨後被獨子取代
幸會
平淡無奇？
我任期的市佔率提昇百分之十二，幾乎…
總之我們不說「取代」，我們…
稱為「生孩子」
當然
很榮幸見到我創造者的創造者
又來了
我發現你沒有提到
你似乎無法讓這傢夥活著
超過廿五分鐘 -廿九分鐘
朱利安，欺騙投資人不算商業模式
掌控恆久程式碼的人就能掌握未來
我們非贏不可
聽著，我…
欣賞你的遠見，站挺
不過董事會衹會再支持你半年
如果你運氣好的話
要是不成功
這一切都會化為烏有，寶貝
我們過去卌年來打造的所有心血
要是我說我找到方法了呢？
（凱文費林，伺服器備份）
這是我第九十五個早餐墨西哥捲
眞的吃不膩，很扯吧？
好吧…
還好家裡不是衹有黛絲執迷不悟
賽斯，你說得對
抱歉，我該更關註你…沒關係
（輸入檔名）
好
對不起啦 -少來
在氣溫零下的地方待三個月很久，我懂
又四天十小時卅二分
誰在算呢？
等一下
什麼意思？
什麼事？
（列印？檢查完成？）
（恭喜）
賽斯
發現什麼了嗎？ -應該是
那行程式碼
那就是他的藏法，有兩行
好像雙螺旋
它就是雙螺旋
黛絲一定會很開心
你認眞？不會再「廿九分鐘掛點」？
如果跟我想的一樣
它就是恆久程式碼
（錄影中）
好
英克爾離線測試三一七a-一
執行恆久程式碼
測試資產穩定性能否突破目前廿九分的限制
開始
準備好就開始 -好
（轉移開始）
關鍵就在技巧
百看不厭
測試開始，廿九分倒數計時
看這次能不能撐下去
戰神是終極士兵
如果出現奇蹟，他在戰場上倒下
我就再做一個給你
全是自有技術，而且隨時…
能犧牲
雅典娜 -歡迎回來，長官
各單位已上線，可供檢查
行程順利嗎？
很有趣，這次不一樣
我見到一對母子
當時在下雨
大氣中凝結的水份，以水滴狀落下的現象
我幾乎能感受到
感受？我不懂
（歡迎瘋空粉）
我是伊芙，冷靜下來，傳訊息
伊芙，我是艾琳，亞傑找你，請回電
還是轉語音信箱
財星五百大企業執行長
手機卻在最重要的夜晚關機？
可惡，伊芙，你在哪？
瘋空博覽會
五、四、三、二、一
我們成功了嗎？它還在
我們改變世界了
你成功了，伊芙，天啊，成功了
英克爾今晚傳出重大消息
執行長伊芙金不克參加該公司備受矚目的
新遊戲《瘋狂空間：恐慌城市》發表會
金極具設計遠見
是該暢銷系列的幕後推手…
我跟幾個董事會成員談過
他們當然大為驚豔
朱利安
繼續 -是
你在幹嘛？ -媽，我想改變世界
怎麼回事？
你駭進英克爾？
衹是瞄一眼，沒人會註意
你怎麼會認為英克爾快找到了？
因為我知道還有誰在找它
誰？
伊芙金
她追隨她妹的腳步
她想找恆久程式碼，我感覺得到
我要找到她，到時候…
我覺得不妥，太冒險了，朱利安
糟糕
（英克爾伺服器農場）
（安全漏洞）
各區出現安全漏洞
程式們，我們的指令很清楚
滲透伺服器核心
擷取伊芙金的使用者檔案
直播倒數五、四、三…
瘋狂空間粉絲，準備好了嗎？
掌聲歡迎英克爾科技長，亞傑辛
牛仔上場 -不
大家好
你們好
謝謝
你好嗎，瘋空博覽會？
我要進去了
（獲準進入英克爾）
我進去了
我是天才，誰曉得你養了一個天才？
惹禍上身
（山姆費林的神秘女郎是誰？）
啟動封鎖程序，切斷網絡存取
我們得立刻應對
啟動安全程序
人們將生活託付給人工智慧
你感到安心嗎？
聽著
每個末日情境
都有醫療突破和科學發現
或許未知帶來的事物沒那麼可怕
如果它的重大缺陷衹是仁慈呢？
這是什麼？他在幹嘛？
不過，你偏好跟眞人對話嗎？
當然，但要是那個人已經聯絡不上了呢？
不在人世了呢？
拿到檔案了
（檔案已下載）
恭喜
趁機快離開吧
程式們，開戰
對！
感謝大家
瘋空粉都怎麼做？
徹底碾壓你
凱厄斯
他失能了，別管他
你撐得住，凱厄斯
有時得犧牲騎士才能逮到對方的皇后
（確認清除資料？）
（有效負載已部署）
對全世界首發最新版的
《瘋狂空間：恐慌城市》
怎麼了？ -那是什麼？
太扯了 -你看到了嗎？
辛先生，你得跟我來
這是技術問題
馬上回來 -這邊請
全都掛了
很好，主控
已取得伊芙金的檔案
目標達成
長官，我想知道凱厄斯程式為何沒重建
我想知道你為何想知道
凱厄斯失能，所以被刪除了
跟任何不照指令運作的程式一樣
你懂嗎？
回答我，主控
當然
我們是隨時可以犧牲的
新任務，主控，找到伊芙金
是
我們好像碰上小型網路攻擊，小朱
但你當然知道了
看來全世界都知道
最好遠離社群媒體幾天
你想跟我玩？那就來玩
我聽說你向董事會提的案子了
但你漏了一個關鍵細節
你有說進攻時間衹有廿九分鐘嗎？
別逼我向報社爆料
你的承諾無法實現
承諾？
就像你們說執行長會在辦公室坐鎮嗎？
事有蹊蹺吧，亞傑？
先是山姆費林，現在是他的繼位者
她在哪，亞傑？你知道嗎？
也許你說得對
也許伊芙瘋了
也許她擅離職守出國，也許…
她躱起來，跟你找同樣的東西
我知道我會賭誰贏
如果你今晚過後還有錢
通話結束
我討厭那個人
非常謝謝你
那些柳橙是我做的，說來話長
停…
你在幹嘛？
一千九百一十三則訊息，好紅喔 -哇
（亞傑辛）
是亞傑，找你的
亞傑，你在那裡嗎？ -我在嗎？
我們的伺服器被暴力破解
就在重大產品發表會上
我們建立的一切都垮了，你得馬上回來
我找到了，亞傑，是眞的
就在黛絲認定的地方，一直都在費林手上
你是說恆久程式碼？
對，已經超過四小時了
沒有退化，沒有不穩，狀態極佳
等下，你說四小時？
對，四小時 -天啊
他一定知道，伊芙
我跟剛狄林傑談過
等下，你跟狄林傑談過？
他在找程式碼，他認為你也是
我們得趕緊行動
伊芙，你表現得太好了
是黛絲的功勞
我正要去英克爾
我們會保住程式碼，我存在隨身碟裡
（存取資料庫中）
我們要重新推出《瘋狂空間》
今天你生日…
亞傑 -今天你生日
（伊芙金）
你好嗎，伊芙？有消息要告訴粉絲嗎？
（科學怪人）
嗨
「我無所畏懼，因而強大」
看來我們剛賣出第一千萬套
（瘋狂空間，史上最暢銷重啟遊戲）
（伊芙金讓英克爾重返顛峰）
伊芙，《瘋狂空間》
凱文費林，無論他在哪
臉上都掛著燦爛微笑
你超成功的
不…
祝你生日快樂…
（黛絲金，一九八八年一月五日生）
（膠質母細胞瘤，存活率百分之廿七點三）
祝你生日快樂，親愛的黛絲
祝你生日快樂
最新消息
與癌癥長期抗戰後，英克爾特別計畫主任
黛絲金在今天病逝
我們聯繫不上她的姊姊伊芙金
（地點：鹽溪海岸）
（鹽溪海岸有限公司，伊芙金，黛絲金）
（登記人：伊芙金）
（飛機尾號：N-黛絲）
（航班追蹤：進場噴射機）
（出發地）
（阿拉斯加，史凱威）
（掃描中…）
（發現異常）
（快轉）
（成熟臍橙樹）
恆久
（發現異常：甜橙，年齡約五小時）
（伊芙金抵達時間：卅八分鐘後）
將殺
我們的英雄在夜色中出征
身上衹揹著衣物
和價値六百萬元、能憑空創造有機物質的
粒子雷射，挺瘋狂的吧？
維護設備的安全，記得…保持低調
好嗎？ -好
嘿
我們可以的
倒數至一時執行指令，通訊檢查
倒數至一時啟動導引導航控制，通訊檢查
列印進行中
第一階段，艙壓正常
Envac引擎開始冷卻
第一階段裝載完成
轉移完成
限你們廿九分鐘內把伊芙金帶來
資產部署已確認，車輛正在途中
目標確認
靠，我太屌了
上前攔截中
（戰神，雅典娜，伊芙）
（攔截）
緊盯目標
（伊芙金）
正協調圍堵向東逃逸的嫌犯
什麼？
那個騎機車的
靠邊停
來啊
（雅典娜，故障）
她去哪了？
快啊
好
快點…
天啊
快啊…
（雅典娜，不明人士）
什麼？
好
天啊，好
天啊
（人類嬰兒）
準備粒子雷射
該用B計畫了
是
快啊
對
好，你想玩？
你究竟是什麼？
我是主控
你想幹嘛？
我要程式碼
它不見了
不，並沒有
我看見她了
與創界網絡建立連結中
準備轉移，倒數十五秒
（戰神，伊芙）
你是…一個程式
（戰神，偵測到猶豫）
你快沒時間了
（同理心反應）
趴在地上
（即將消解）
將她轉移到創界網絡裡
記者現在就在市區
我可以說這不是精心設計的特技表演
三名騎士… -你做了什麼？
（市區飛車追逐，傷亡慘重）
你怎麼能這麼魯莽？
等世人看見我創造的成果
就會諒解一切
你是這麼想的？
你認為你掌控了局面？
並沒有
相信我們能改變世界
是這家公司存續的關鍵
卻也能讓公司毀於一旦
你的職責是明白其中的差別
生物體轉移程序進行中
數位重建已啟動
百分之廿數位化
百分之卌數位化
百分之六十五數位化
百分之九十五數位化
數位化完成
執行診斷並掃描損壞情況
伊芙金身份光碟已啟動
哇
我在哪裡？
狄林傑系統中央處理器
等下，什麼？
我們已經確認序列
使用者擁有程式碼
程式碼？
程式碼？我沒有程式碼，我摧毀隨身碟了
使用者，安靜
程式碼不衹在隨身碟裡，也在你體內
不管是否記得，你看過它，那就夠了
但… -她的光碟不穩定
說明何謂不穩定
擷取程式碼可能導致載體消解
指令很清楚
隔離程式碼，進行擷取
収到
等下，不…
停
雅典娜說得對
我們衹遵從一名使用者的指令
（戰神，來訊）
（載入訊息中）
（擷取伊芙金的恆久程式碼）
（可能造成載體消解）
如果使用者消解，會剩下什麼？
什麼也不剩
她在創界網絡不會留下蹤跡？
不會，長官
擷取程式碼，刪除載體
可是，擷取恆久程式碼
會將載體從創界網絡和您的世界刪除
（執行這項命令）
（將無法復原）
很久以前，有一種武器叫戰神
戰神對朱利安狄林傑言聽計從
朱利安狄林傑賺進一兆元
還用鮮血讓他在歷史上留名
無論這些感受來自什麼操作錯誤
我都會找到它，把它從你身上剔除
我說得清楚嗎？
十分清楚
程式退下
那個怪物也說：「我無所畏懼
因而強大」
如何？ -使用者身體不適
靜候指令再擷取
身體不適？ -是的
說明何謂身體不適
他困在車陣中
不，他在歌劇院
他穿著綠色襪子站在富士山頂
用曼陀林演奏《帶手槍的媽媽》
我已經下達命令
創造者身體不適
等我們収到進一步指令再擷取
我說得清楚嗎？
清楚，長官
程式們退下
我能信任你嗎？
這問題很複雜，你有多少時間？
六十秒，快回答，你的生命週期就靠它了
我沒有生命週期
你有，還剩下五十四秒
我可以信任你嗎？
我希望可以，但應該不行
（雅典娜，來訊）
主控在哪裡？
長官，主控出現故障跡象
指令受到的威脅都必須剷除
擷取程式碼，把他們兩個都刪除
你懂嗎？
朱利安狄林傑呢？ -不能信任他
他認為所有人事物都可以犧牲
我失算了
我們有新指令
雅典娜，沒必要這樣
刪除他
我沒事…
他們要前往轉移入口
他們躱進創界網絡了
準備無人機
刪除戰神
帶使用者回來 -収到
（無人機儲備庫）
剛才發生什麼事？
我違抗指令
什麼指令？
從你的光碟取回程式碼，刪除載體
狄林傑叫你刪除我？
抓緊
他們在哪裡？
掃描第三與第四象限
十八區沒有發現
我們要去哪？
轉移入口，離開創界網絡的唯一途徑
你會在眞實世界重建
理論上會跟以前完全一樣
理論上？ -應該吧
七十二區有動靜
瞄準目標
射擊他們
你想回家，我能幫你
但我需要一點回報
我說過我沒有程式碼
你找到它一次，就能再找到第二次
你要交給狄林傑？
不是給狄林傑
是給我
就這樣說定了？
我們說定了嗎？
對，我知道去哪找程式碼，快帶我離開
目標卌五秒後接近轉移入口
（離線）
無人機故障、離線
註意
（轉移開始）
請保持距離
覆寫指令無回應
怎麼了？ -誰授權的？
（轉移開始）
這源自創界網絡內部
安全程序警報
朱利安？
全體探員立刻向轉移層報到
清空本區域
叫大家離開 -未授權列印進行中
清空中央區域
轉移完成 -過去
（戰神）
唉呀呀
我被我的程式背叛了
它自己想要恆久程式碼
伊芙，你們講好了？
它帶你離開創界網絡
你把小木偶變成小男孩？
你漏掉你為了一個軟體
不惜殺人的部份
是它說的嗎？ -廿八分卌一秒
戰神
我希望你們心想事成
沒有第二次機會，無法重來
這是你擁有的最後廿九分鐘
最好善加利用
（沙迪斯）
我眞該主修英文的
（戰神，雅典娜）
轉移完成
你要找到伊芙金
送她回創界網絡，把恆久程式碼交給我
不擇手段
你瞭解你的指令嗎？
主控
遵命，長官
乖女孩
時間有限
那是我見過最酷的東西
知道凱文費林是誰嗎？
當然，前衛程式設計師
數位新領域的先驅
一九八九年失蹤
我在費林伺服器的備份中發現恆久程式碼
那個伺服器在英克爾的市區辦公室
我們能在…
廿六分零九秒內抵達
伊芙，你的計畫有兩大缺失
好
第一，英克爾在十五公里外
而我們這輛車目前的速度欠佳
天啊
第二，我們需要粒子雷射
我們需要手機
不敢相信我會這麼做
抱歉，看到沒？這是我
讓我用你的手機，我助理會匯一萬元給你
我需要你的手機
賽斯，你在哪？
伊芙，這是誰的手機？
聽我說，我要你十五分後到英克爾
情況都還好嗎？
賽斯，帶粒子雷射來
英克爾，十五分鐘，瞭解
那是我的車
我會再匯五萬元給你
喂，那是我的車
二點零四汽缸，一百卅八匹馬力
差勁
喂，那是我的車
那是我的車
（消解時間倒數）
天啊
伊芙 -如何？
我在想你曾經告訴令妹
你寧願從沒重啟過《瘋狂空間》
然後你又說…
天啊，你當然看過我所有訊息
對，我全看過，每一則
哇
大多是私人性質的資訊
有些涉及高度隱私
我就是欲罷不能
什麼？
流行尖端樂團
一九八二年英國單曲榜第八名
他們的風格簡潔、朗朗上口
經典的八零年代電音
令人十分振奮
十六分廿秒
好，你喜歡八零年代流行樂和數位監控我
我的指令是殺你，伊芙
駭客行為相較之下溫和多了
天啊 -我想聲明
我認為你沒有什麼好羞愧的
《瘋狂空間》讓數億人得到娛樂
而且是個滿酷的遊戲
總之，你跟你妹說設計遊戲
讓你感到空虛消沉
難道你的工作是娛樂和獲利
她的工作是改善人類處境嗎？
你的訊息顯示你很在意
自己無法達到她的標準
那種感受一定很複雜
尤其她又是妹妹
好，小心講話
對了，我認為你不該辭職
什麼意思？
你從山上回來後的計畫
如果我解讀正確
是把恆久程式碼交給英克爾
讓他們去進行後續規劃，不是嗎？
這下我懂了
你完成她的工作，藉此留住和她的連結
現在呢？
當人類很辛苦
讓生活美好的東西
也會帶來痛苦，像是愛、失去
（至英克爾大樓時間）
（消解時間倒數）
你一定非常想她
喂…
搞什麼？
（英克爾）
看這個傢夥
（英克爾廣場南側）
看誰來了 -嗨
很高興你來了，金小姐，大家都在找你
好久不見，有點趕，我就…
伊芙，你得戴識別證
好，裘琳…
裘琳，她的識別證在這裡
也有他的嗎？
沒有，他不是一起的
他是 -他是
從哪裡說起都行啊
這是我的男友戰神
不是啦
狄林傑創界網絡的主控安全程式
戰神，他賽斯，賽斯，他戰神，天啊
幸會
眞客氣
戰神，是那個戰爭之神嗎？
對
酷，你是希臘人，好讚
你說他是安全程式，意思是…
對，他不是人類 -他不是人類
來自中央處理器內部
我們要拍耶誕節影片嗎？
三分鐘後消解
你能處理嗎，賽斯？
可以
我不需要幫忙
好
天啊
（凱文費林辦公室）
我在這伺服器的備份裡發現恆久程式碼
果眞是第一代
果眞很廢，對吧？
這樣講對你的祖先不敬，抱歉
我要幾分鐘才能組好
不急，兩分十八秒
（創界網絡）
雷射一開，我們就送你進網絡
你進去後得自己蒐尋，但相信我…
（數位新領域）
恆久程式碼在裡面 -我該預期什麼？
要我猜的話，想想八零年代
八零年代
我喜歡八零年代
一分卅一秒
來吧
（粒子雷射：上線）
請幫我
都好了
配接器
發現程式碼就到入口，我們會帶你出來
我會從外面啟動它
我可以信任你嗎？
我希望可以
但應該不行 -應該不行
是啊
幸好我們沒有信任問題
否則，我能想像…
我能拔掉插頭
把你留在比我手機更低階的創界網絡
直到永遠
我想過這一點
我也是
抱歉
死馬當活馬醫
也許馬還沒死
你說得對
我是很想她
想個不停
雅典娜，她來了
那是什麼？
雅典娜
等下，誰？
賽斯，雷射…
好，立刻啟動系統
連到費林創界網絡
發射雷射
她在幹嘛？
她在等我的時間到…
（雅典娜，消解時間倒數）
然後就會來抓你
快好了，準備好
快點…
戰神，到雷射前面
準備好了
你在幹嘛？
快啊
計畫改變
不… -不…
（即將消解）
眞的有用
（轉移完成）
他進去了 -太好了
閃開
伊芙
該回創界網絡了
別碰她
（二號玩家，遊戲結束）
你很頑固，使用者
（感覺：不明）
（即將消解）
（消解倒數）
什麼？
嗨
我們贏了嗎？
她會回來的
戰神
他出不來
八零年代
（資料單位：位元）
二進制位元
你是一個位元 -是
我在找東西，你能幫我嗎？
是，是，是
經典
我周圍遭到大規模破壞
（英克爾遇襲：該怪狄林傑系統？）
明目張膽的攻擊令居民目瞪口呆
現在有人推測狄林傑系統
與這起事件有關
但有關單位依然三緘其口
民眾和官方都想知道
這是預謀攻擊還是科技失控？
（轉移開始）
又怎麼了？
這是幹嘛？
我的程式碼呢？
喂！
你在幹嘛？誰給你指令的？
是你，長官
（資產轉移中）
（轉移開始）
這是什麼？
警告
不…這太大了，雅典娜，太大了
朱利安
你玩完了
董事會現在要拔掉你的頭銜
我會重新接管公司
不可以，不行
我可以
不能這樣下去
你不能…
我的當務之急
是關閉恆久計畫 -不…媽，嫑
嫑怕
我們為創界網絡死了上千次
你衹要死一次
不…
媽
障礙已排除
你做了什麼？
我在執行我的指令
逮捕伊芙金，不擇手段帶她回創界網絡
掃描其他障礙
（掃描中）
請保持距離
撐住，媽，撐下去
（轉移進行中）
（覆寫遭拒）
（殺光所有人）
不
費林
你好，程式
天啊，不妙
多人通報上層區域有失火與破壞…
伊芙？
我們辦公室怎麼了？
亞傑，沒時間了
狄林傑反轉粒子雷射的方向
把我送進他們的伺服器
不是用這臺，是他們的 -不可能
是一個瘋婆子幹的，她把我…很誇張
我看見一個複雜的世界
能量包如同車輛般移動
留下光的軌跡
程式擁有人類外型
我見到有史以來最先進的人工智慧
他叫戰神
戰爭之神，不過他人超好的
抱歉，繼續 -現在
戰神在費林的原始伺服器裡
他在找恆久程式碼
我得帶他回來，而我要做到
就得修復這雷射
我不懂，你是活的嗎？
我存在於這一刻裡，因為你也在
你存在的映射
你是什麼來歷？
我是戰神，狄林傑安全網絡的主控
狄林傑？
我們都知道你無法從那裡到這裡來
中間去過別的地方嗎？
對那裡有何看法？
一言難盡
你也能幫我說一遍
眞妙，很幽默
你在找什麼？
恆久
應該說恆久程式碼
近來發生了怪事
我質疑我的指令，違抗指令
故障的程式想要活下去
眞的嗎？
我為什麼該幫你？
不，重點不是我
已經不是了
我有朋友身陷險境，她需要我幫忙
有意思
亞傑，傳提示給我 -好
伊芙 -先別煩我，賽斯
好，你確定嗎？
好像有一架識別者往這邊飛來
那是什麼東西？
是雅典娜
她回來了
衹要狄林傑網絡上線，她就會一直來
抓到我，她就能得到恆久程式碼
雷射，雅典娜的雷射
狄林傑使用一種無線直連協定
我們用剩下的雷射探測，追溯返航路徑
一旦連線，就能破壞整個狄林傑網絡
那是唯一徹底阻止她的方法
伊芙，你在說什麼？她就在那裡
我該走了 -等下，什麼？
我會盡量牽制她
什麼？ -我幫你們爭取時間
伊芙 -你們可以的
（追蹤目標中，伊芙金）
沒錯，我應該有問題
或者，也許你有好的地方
也許你衹是在學習
我們都應該那麼做
當年科技剛開始萌芽時
我會想：「我們進展得好快」
進展快，就會拋下一些東西
這世紀出生的人有多少個聽過莫札特？
我喜歡莫札特
但老實說，我比較喜歡流行尖端
是嗎？怎麼說？
一個被譽為西方文明史上
最偉大的作曲家
一個是八零年代的合成流行樂團
但他們的音樂兼具實驗性與流行元素
再加上…
怎麼了？
我無法用言語形容對流行尖端的喜愛
那衹是…
什麼？
一種感覺
非常好
一艘大如摩天樓的飛船剛進入本市領空
並前往市區…
你…
是你造成的
今晚，軍方…
了不起，完全分段的零信任架構
可以抵禦垂直、橫向或混合攻擊
（狄林傑網絡，連線中斷）
可惡，連不上 -這裡也是
（遭拒）
（瘋狂空間）
請立即撤離本區域
那是什麼？找反恐特警組 -請求支援
天啊
來啊，再靠近一點
（伊芙金）
毒蛇一號呼叫基地，看見敵方
目視確認目標
攻擊，狐狸二號飛彈已發射
未命中，飛彈已被攔截
註意，敵方護航戰鬥機快速逼近
収到，渡鴉一號，評估威脅態勢
毒蛇一號，看見多架敵機
確認對方有敵意
求救…我被擊中了
毒蛇一號，彈射逃生
（發射）
各位，各位
天啊，有幾百個
他們在追伊芙
進不了狄林傑伺服器就沒東西可救了
渡鴉一號呼叫基地，敵機發動攻擊
我在防禦狀態
有多架敵機，轉向主要目標
我被擊中了，彈射逃生
準備好了嗎？
希望如此，無法回頭了
恆久
說來好玩
我發現它時就是這麼叫它
我現在學聰明了
應該叫短暫程式碼
後門通往我的舊實驗室
一次機會
你衹有一次
一次機會…
就是我要的
我喜歡
你不斷令我驚奇
那我們就在地面進行
（創界網絡）
（費林）
（抵達轉移區所需時間）
據報上面可能有一個平民
代表可能有人遭到挾持
雅典娜，她一定抓到伊芙了
進入山區
喂…
我們很快就回創界網絡
將軍，感謝你今晚撥空接受訪問
艾琳，賽斯
（連接狄林傑網絡中）
（連線已建立）
停止計時器
不會吧，你進去了？
我用角落辦公室是有原因的
嘿
你回來了
你怎麼…
姑且說我有朋友幫忙
等下，狄林傑網絡…
亞傑和賽斯…
快走 -不
戰神
（戰神，消解錯誤）
你做了什麼？
你沒時間了，雅典娜
而你要沒命了
我會殺了你，再回來找她
她要的是你
讓她拿到程式碼就完了
你曾擁有一切
快跑 -不
最先進、最強大的能力，你卻輕易放棄
為了她？
快跑
這是你的末日
有效負載準備轉移
運送中
（狄林傑，執行網絡清除，自毀）
（傳送有效負載）
希望伊芙是對的
警告，不明檔案傳入
為了自己追求生命
你考慮過這對創界網絡的影響嗎？
我們接到命令，它是我們的使命
它不是我們的使命
是我們的設定
我們的使命尚未決定
（連接狄林傑網絡中）
（連線失敗）
（系統離線）
結束了
無法回頭了
不
這次不行
他們成功了
天啊
我遵照我的指令
我知道
現在…
你的指令是什麼？
我不確定
到時候就知道了
狄林傑系統今晚面臨嚴密蒐查
外界懷疑它可能涉及
使本市陷入動蕩的一連串毀滅性攻擊
聯邦當局已證實正積極調查
該公司近期的活動
許多事件直接指向執行長朱利安狄林傑
當局已指派探員訊問執行長與他的母親
聯絡董事會…
（系統嚴重故障）
（雷射校正中）
釐清相關情形
此外，本市依然一片混亂
急難救護單位不堪負荷
有整片區域遭到大規模破壞
（關閉）
（重啟雷射中）
（重啟失敗）
朱利安狄林傑，我們是警察
你被包圍了
開門，高舉雙手走出來
（雷射系統上線）
（上線）
快啊
（雷射校正中）
（轉移已反轉）
破門
警察！
待在原地
繼續監控所有出口
查理九號，我們在最後指定位置…
黃色六號，在前面，快去…
你還好嗎？
好像有肋骨斷了
你還會辭職嗎？
不，我不會放棄任何東西
很好
我有一些想法
是嗎？很好 -嗯
這世界需要你，伊芙
創界網絡需要你
說來奇怪，恆久…
有個智者說它應該叫「短暫程式碼」
我想那就是生命的特點
沒有什麼是恆久的
沒錯
確實沒有
是啊
你要去哪裡？
我有一些想法
英克爾在執行長伊芙金領導下
推動產業轉型
（費林不死）
以過去難以想像的方式形塑生活
由於發現了恆久程式碼
該公司取得了革命性的進展
在氣候脆弱區域種植作物
針對耐藥性癌癥研發藥物
以及加速替代燃料的開發
英克爾致力於探索數位新領域
推動科技與生命的融合發展
以改善人類的生活品質
事實上，創新始終是英克爾的核心
八零年代，深具遠見的凱文費林
想像一個遊戲之外的未來
大膽躍入數位新領域
如今，那個願景已經成眞
我差點忘了
明信片？誰還用郵寄的？ -不知道
我沒看
親愛的伊芙
自從上次見到你
我都過著所謂的「外網絡」生活
我故意用雙關語
我在旅行中見到不可思議的事物
儘管奇妙、美麗，我卻發覺生活…
呃，一言難盡
有時我會想百年後我們會在哪裡
（神秘夥伴在英克爾有何角色？）
跟我同類的人如何融入未來
我覺得可能不衹有我有這些疑問
現在，我想世人還沒準備要認識我
但我正在認識這個世界
所以，等那一刻終於來臨
就像我一個好友說的
「或許未知帶來的終究沒那麼可怕」
（半圓頂小屋）
期待再相見
你的朋友戰神上
（英克爾）
薩克…